Email

d.labastida.t@gmail.com

Address

Carrera 19a 107-41 Colombia, Bogot á D.C.

Phone

(+52)5522688517

Date of birth

Apr 15, 1995

Nationality

Mexican

Link

https://www.linkedin.com/in/diegooctavio-labastida-tolalpa-6068141 47/

Skills

Java

Spring Boot

SQL

React JS

Python

R

Angular

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Languages

English

Intermediate

German

Elementary

French

Intermediate

Diego Octavio Labastida Tolalpa

Industrial Robotics Engineer

Industrial Robotics Engineer with skills in programming and computing.

Knowledge in back end and front end programming languages such as Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python and R. Experience in development of WEB applications with monolithic and microservices architecture using frameworks, use of cloud environments and data analysis with data mining technologies.

Experience

Senior Development Engineer

Sitrack.com Bogotá D.C., Colombia

Apr 2021 - Present

Responsabilities

- Java Team Leader to develop custom applications with Spring Boot
- · Ai-Hydro project leader with patent numbers USA: 11348014 COL: 21581
- Development with Java 8+ and Holanda Catalina Framework: Ai-Hydro, Route Optimizer and Integration of IoT technologies (GPS, Cameras and Sensors)
- Data processing and use of supervised, unsupervised and reinforcement learning algorithms for intelligent systems with Java EE, Python and R

Senior Development Engineer

Sitrack.com Ciudad de México

Feb 2020 - Present

Responsibilities

- Designed and implemented web applications such as vehicle monitoring sites with Java EE 8, Python and React js.
- Collaborated with international teams (AR, COL, BR, CHL, MX) for the integration of tracking systems.
- Implement "Scoretrack" application with driving behavior algorithm.
- Design of data science models for the classification and prediction of behaviors in App Scoretrack.
- Development of tools to Sitrack.io platform with Java EE 8, Hollanda Catalina framework and React in a microservices environment with Docker, Kubernetes and Gitlab CI

Software Development Engineer

MasterTrain, Ciudad de México

Dec 2018 - Nov 2019

Responsibilities

- Development of Web applications and web services (MVC) with Java 8
- DataBases: MySQL, MongoDB y Postgresql.
- · Administrated of Versions control (GIT).
- · Implementated of Web Services with SpringBoot and JWT
- · Development of Web applications with Angular8 and Express.js

Software Development Engineer

MasterTrain, Mérida, Yucatán

Nov 2019 - Jan 2020

Responsibilities

- · Administration of WebSites and platforms.
- · Administration of Hosting and Domains.
- · Development with Java Technologies and Frameworks like Spring and Hibernate
- · Development of CRM and ERP applications and web services (MVC).

Java and Web Developer

Dealer's Club Mayorista Ciudad de México

Feb 2018 - Nov 2018

Responsibilities

- Development of Web applications and web services (MVC).
- · Created and modificated of Stored procedures in DB Informix and SQL
- Server
- · Web Services Rest Full with Spring MVC.
- · Administrated of Versions control (GIT).
- Implementated of Web Services with SpringBoot and JWT for ecommerce (HPOnline).
- Update and maintenance of Web applications (Website, CRM, ERP).

Assessor

Casa Ortiz Rines Industriales y Montacargas S.A. de C.V. Tlalnepantla, México

Jan 2017 - Feb 2018

Responsibilities

- Drawing of Rims, Wheel Assembly and Axle Shaft for Trucks, Industrial
- · Vehicles and Forklifts with SolidWorks.
- · Design of special rims whit special assembly.
- · Modification of Rims and Axle Shaft whit customer specifications.
- · Supervision of wheel manufacturing.
- · Inventory control.

Education

Industrial Robotics Engineer

Instituto Politécnico Nacional Ciudad de México

Aug 2014 - Dec 2017

Master in Data Science

Universitat Oberta de Catalunya Cataluña, España

Feb 2021 - Present